export const questions = [
  [
    {
      question: "Who is Adams wife?",
      answer: "Eve",
      choices: ["Rabeka", "Jezebel", "Eve", "Leah"]
    },
    {
      question: "Who was Abels brother",
      answer: "Cain",
      choices: ["Cain", "Joshua", "Lazarus", "Noah"]
    },
    {
      question: "What did Noah build",
      answer: "The Ark",
      choices: ["A nice chair", "A beaded necklace", "The Ark", "A house"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question:
        "After Jesus was arrested, which apostle disowned him three times? ",
      answer: "Peter",
      choices: ["Judas", "Peter", "John", "Andrew"]
    },
    {
      question:
        "To what city was Saul traveling when he encountered a great and blinding light?",
      answer: "Damascus",
      choices: ["Jerusalem", "Athens", "Tarsus", "Damascus"]
    },
    {
      question:
        "You will need faith as your ______ to stop the fiery arrows of the enemy.",
      answer: "Shield",
      choices: ["Belt", "Breast Plate", "Shield", "Shoes"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Matthew was a _________.",
      answer: "Tax collector",
      choices: ["Tax collector", "Fisherman", "Priest", "Farmer"]
    },
    {
      question: "Lot was saved from _________.",
      answer: "Sodom",
      choices: ["Haran", "Sodom", "Gomorrah", "Egypt"]
    },
    {
      question:
        "According to Paul which is the greatest of the imperishable qualities? ",
      answer: "Love",
      choices: ["Faith", "Love", "Mercy", "Hope"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Who wrote the book of Revalations?",
      answer: "John",
      choices: ["John", "Paul", "James", "Peter"]
    },
    {
      question: "Who is the high priest of Jerusalem who put Jesus on trial? ",
      answer: "Caiaphas",
      choices: ["Herod", "Ananias ", "Josephus", "Caiaphas"]
    },
    {
      question: "What was the name of Adam’s third son?",
      answer: "Seth",
      choices: ["Enosh", "Jared", "Seth", "Mahalalel"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Which of the following was not a judge?",
      answer: "Laban",
      choices: ["Laban", "Gideon", "Deborah", "Samson"]
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following was a judge?",
      answer: "Othniel",
      choices: ["Hezikia", "Zephenia", "Gabe", "Othniel"]
    },
    {
      question: "The mother of Abrahams first son",
      answer: "Hagar",
      choices: ["Sara", "Hagar", "Sarah", "Adah"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Isaac's first wife",
      answer: "Rebekah",
      choices: ["Rizpah", "Rebekah", "Leah", "Rachel"]
    },
    {
      question: "This was Egypts primary souce of water.",
      answer: "The Nile",
      choices: ["The Jordan", "The Nile", "Red Sea", "Caspian Sea"]
    },
    {
      question: "What did King Solomon ask for from God",
      answer: "Wisdom",
      choices: ["Wisdom", "Victory in battle", "Power", "Wealth"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Which Gospel is written by a doctor?",
      answer: "Luke",
      choices: ["Matthew", "Mark", "Luke", "John"]
    },
    {
      question:
        "God promised Abraham that his descendants would be as numerous as _________.",
      answer: "the sand on the seashore",
      choices: [
        "the fish in the sea",
        "the grass in the fields",
        "the stars in the solar system",
        "the sand on the seashore"
      ]
    },
    {
      question: "Who found Isaac's wife",
      answer: "Abraham's servant",
      choices: [
        "Abraham",
        "Lot's cousin",
        "Melchizedek's wife",
        "Abraham's servant"
      ]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Who is Samuel's mom?",
      answer: "Hannah",
      choices: ["Deborah", "Hannah", "Tamar", "Priscilla"]
    },
    {
      question: "Who allowed Israelite spies into their home",
      answer: "Rehab",
      choices: ["Jeshua", "Jephthah", "Ehud", "Rehab"]
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which of Josephs brothers said that they should not kill Joseph?",
      answer: "Rueben",
      choices: ["Benjamin", "Judah", "Rueben", "Joshua"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "What type of insect did John the Baptist eat in the desert?",
      answer: "Locusts",
      choices: ["Hornets", "Locusts", "Grasshopers", "None of these"]
    },
    {
      question: "Muslim's believe they are the descendants of _________.",
      answer: "Ishmael",
      choices: ["Esau", "Ishmael", "Lot", "Joseph"]
    },
    {
      question: "Who was Davids first wife?",
      answer: "Michal",
      choices: ["Saphira", "Huldah", "Michal", "Phoebe"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "Who asked Pilate for Jesus’ body after the crucifixion? ",
      answer: "Joseph of Arimathea",
      choices: ["Simon of Joppa", "Joseph of Arimathea", "Martha", "Simeon"]
    },
    {
      question: 'What does the word "epistle" mean?',
      answer: "Letter",
      choices: ["Words", "Letter", "Book", "Writings"]
    },
    {
      question:
        "What is the longest book of the New Testament? (by word count)",
      answer: "Luke",
      choices: ["Luke", "Revelations", "Acts", "Matthew"]
    }
  ],
  [
    {
      question: "What is the shortest book in the New Testament? ",
      answer: "2 John",
      choices: ["Philemon", "Jude", "2 John", "2 Corinthians"]
    },
    {
      question: "Who were the first disciples called to follow Jesus?",
      answer: "Peter and Andrew",
      choices: [
        "James and John",
        "Peter and Andrew",
        "Philip and Thomas",
        "Matthew and Simon"
      ]
    },
    {
      question: "Paul was shipwrecked on what island?",
      answer: "Malta",
      choices: ["Malta", "Creet", "Paros", "Capri"]
    }
  ]
];

export const skipOptions = [
  {
    question: "Where was Moses born?",
    answer: "Egypt",
    choices: ["The Promised Land", "Egypt", "Ur", "Hebron"]
  },
  {
    question:
      "How many times did Naaman clean himself in the Jordan in order to be healed?",
    answer: "7",
    choices: ["5", "12", "3", "7"]
  },
  {
    question: "Who is Jacobs oldest brother?",
    answer: "Esau",
    choices: ["Esau", "Abbel", "Ishmael", "Lot"]
  }
];
